

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Checkpoint Firewall Automation Cisco Platform Automation Network Automation Ansible JSON / YAML / XML Python Programming Kotlin & Java Programming Go Programming (Recently started) Git Version Control Docker (Recently started) Android Development Checkpoint Firewall Security Fortinet Firewall Security Cisco ASA Firewall Security AWS Security Groups Networking Cisco Networking F5 BigIP Load Balancing Flask API & GO API Firebase Basic Linux Interactions

PERSONAL SKILLS

Motivated
Reliable and professional
Organized
Fast learner
Flexible with new technologies
Always ready to learn more
Fluent in English & French

MERVIN HEMARAJU

NETWORK & DEVOPS ADMINISTRATOR

ABOUT

An experienced Network & DevOps Administrator with a demonstrated history of working in the telecommunication's industry. Skilled in networking, Android development and DevOps automation. Develops my own applications and APIs to facilitate my life and for fun. I am always up to learning and building new things. For all my works, please visit my GitHub link found below in the Social section

EDUCATION



UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY - MAURITIUS

Class of 2015

Degree in Computer Science with Network Security



CISCO INC.

Self Study 2019

Cisco Certified Network Associate - Routing & Switching



CHECKPOINT SECUIRTY

Self Study 2020

Checkpoint Certified Security Administrator R80



CISCO INC.

~ ONGOING

Cisco Certified DevNet Associate

EXTRAS



CREATOR & OWNER OF LOCKY

Locky is an Android application, build in native Kotlin code, that i have created. The app is free for use. The repository is public on my GitHub. Locky can be found on the Google Play Store through the link below: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.th3pl4gu3.locky_offline

CONTACT

P: +230 5 800 1196

E: mervinhemaraju16@gmail.com

W: www.th3pl4gu3.com

SOCIAL



www.linkedin.com/in/mervinh16



www.github.com/mervin16



+230 5 800 1196

WORK EXPERIENCE (1 OF 2)



LINKBYNET INDIAN OCEAN

Phoenix, Mauritius

Network & DevOps Administrator| 18 October 2019 - Present

Network Administrator:

Worked on several firewall technologies such as Checkpoint, Fortinet, Netfilter but mainly Checkpoint

Worked on AWS Cloud technology to manage security groups

Performed several network flow management which was impacting thousands of users around the globe

Performed SSL installation on F5 Load Balancer

Performed SSL installation on HAProxy

Deployed Virtual Servers on F5 Load Balancer.

Worked on Cisco ASA to manage flows for customers.

Deployed a Checkpoint Firewall in High Availability cluster mode from scratch in LAB environment

Deployed several Arista Switches and configured them with VLAN in LAB environments

DevOps Administrator:

Built and deployed Python Scripts to improve administrators' workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed

 $\label{thm:condition} \mbox{Automated several tasks on Checkpoint Firewall which improved workflow and ticket handling.}$

Managed Python scripts and Ansible playbooks in production environment to automate complex and time consuming tasks.



ORANGE BUSINESS SERVICES

Ebene, Mauritius

Video Network Specialist | 15 February 2018 - 11 October 2019

Main Role: Worked as a dedicated support for General Electric Company on Cisco Telepresence endpoints. Worked with Core devices such as Cisco Unified Call Manager & Telepresence Management Suite to register endpoints and perform troubleshooting in case of failing devices. Worked with General Electric Network team to troubleshoot issues on the network. Liaised directly with Cisco in need for a return merchandise authorization. Worked with Cisco engineers to troubleshoot issues on failing Telepresence devices.

Side Projects: Designed and coded a C# based Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) application to help experts with a concise follow up on tickets internally in Orange Business Services. They used to do ticket follow up manually. I advised them with the WPF approach and designed the whole program for them.

WORK EXPERIENCE (2 OF 2)



proximity Intern | 01 August 2016 - 27 February 2017

Worked on small Java Projects including Java Server Pages | Learned Core Programming in Java | Worked with MongoDB Database to connect to a Java Website | Worked on the front-end team for 3 months | Learned front-end technologies such as Sass, CSS Grids, Jade/Pug